Guide to the Sir George Hubert Wilkins Papers
The Ohio State University. Byrd Polar and Climate Research Center Archival Program.
- Series V: Films/Sound Recordings, 1928-1958; 12 c.f.
  - "Ellsworth Trans-Antarctic", 2 reels 16mm, ca 1930s (Box OV-17, Folder 3)
    DVD available at: 054-358-4 item #25; VHS video available at 054-310-8, item 31, 00-45-54-03 thru 00-51-29-07 (shorter of the two reels); and 00-00-41-06 thru 00-39-36-00 (longer of the two reels); shot list available with video
  - "Nautilus: Mostly Spitzbergen and Pack Ice" Marked Negative, 16mm film, 1931 (Box OV-17, Folder 4)
    VHS video available at 054-310-8, item 31, 00-11-45-26 thru 00-35-45-27; DVD available in 054-310-8
  - 16mm reel of film, No title, Undated (Box OV-17, Folder 5)
    VHS video available at 054-310-8, item 31, 00-39-39-19 thru 00-11-46-29
  - "Nautilus: Actual Sounds and Voices Recorded during its Historic Voyage Under the North Pole" USS Nautilus 1958 Trip Sound Recording 33 1/3 Long Play (Box OV-18, Folder 1)
  - "Nautilus: Actual Sounds and Voices Recorded during Its Historic Boyage Under the North Pole" USS Nautilus 1958 Trip Sound Recording 45 (Box OV-18, Folder 2)
  - Sound Recording: No Title, Undated (Box OV-18, Folder 3)
  - Sound Recording: By Columbia Recording Corp: No title, Undated (Box OV-18, Folder 4)
    both sides are Lady Suzanne singing music that sounds like it has been prepared for the stage.
  - Sound Recording: "Sir Hubert Wilkins Spot on 'As Strange As It Seems'", December 12, 1940 (Box OV-18, Folder 5)
    preservation master available in 054-310-7, item 30; enhanced audio cassette available in 054-358-4, item 9
  - Sound Recording: No Title, Undated (Box OV-18, Folder 6)
  - Sound Recording: Program NO 18" Music and Flowers - 'Flowers in the Polar Regions' Guest Speaker Sir Hubert Wilkins, Explorer", 1937 (Box OV-18, Folder 7)
    preservation master available in 054-310-7, item 31; enhanced audio cassette available in 054-358-4, item 9
  - Sound Recording: "Program of Lady Suzanne Wilkins and John Swinburne", July 2, 1941 (Box OV-18, Folder 8)
    preservation master available in 054-310-7, item 33; enhanced audio cassette available in 054-358-4, item 11
  - Ellsworth Antarctic Expedition, 16mm, 1930s (Box S2-1, Folder 1)
    DVD available at: 054-358-4 item #24; shotlist available: J:ArchivedDeptARVPolarWilkinsFilm Shotlists
  - Graf Zeppelin Flight, 16mm, 1929 (Box S2-1, Folder 2)
    VHS video available at 054-310-8, item #44 and 46 (2 copies); 00-29-35-00 thru 00-39-14-00; DVD available in 054-310-8
  - Algiers, Italy, Castle (Ellsworth's?), 16mm, 1930s (Box S2-1, Folder 3)
    VHS video available at 054-310-8, item #45 and 47 (2 copies), 00-25-38-00 thru 00-36-16-00; honeymoon
  - Wilkins-Hearst, Ellsworth, 16mm, 1929, 1934 (Box S2-1, Folder 4)
    VHS video available at 054-310-8, item #44 and 46 (2 copies), 00-40-50-00 thru 00-52-52-00, Ellsworth Expedition
  - Hawaii, Ellsworth Antarctic Plane, Dock, 16mm, 1930s (Box S2-1, Folder 5)
    VHS video available at 054-310-8, item #44 and 46 (2 copies), 00-52-55-00 thru 00-59-01-00, 1938 trip to Australia with Suzanne
  - Military: Snow Scenes. Testing (includes sleeping bags, panels) 16mm, ca 1940s - 1950s (Box S2-1, Folder 6)
  - Ellsworth/Arctic?, Lockheed Vega, 16mm, ca 1928-1930s (Box S2-1, Folder 7)
    VHS video available at 054-310-8, item #45 and 47 (2 copies), 00-00-48-00 thru 00-07-36-00, various expeditions
  - Military: Testing (includes panels in the snow): 16mm, ca 1940s-1950s (Box S2-1, Folder 8)
  - Wilkins-Hearst 2nd Year, 16mm, 1929 (Box S2-1, Folder 9)
  - Ellsworth Antarctic Expedition: Reel no. 1, 1st year, 16mm, Undated (Box S2-2, Folder 10)
    DVD available at: 054-358-4 item #25
  - Ellsworth Antarctic Expedition: Reel no. 2, 1st year, 16mm, Undated (Box S2-2, Folder 11)
  - Ellsworth Antarctic Expedition: Reel no. 3, 1st year, 16mm, Undated (Box S2-2, Folder 12)
  - Ellsworth Antarctic Expedition: Reel no. 1, 2nd year, 16mm, 161-162-1 (Box S2-2, Folder 13)
  - Ellsworth Antarctic Expedition: Reel no. 2, 2nd year, 16mm, Undated (Box S2-2, Folder 14)
  - Ellsworth Antarctic Expedition: Reel no. 3, 2nd year, 16mm, Undated (Box S2-2, Folder 15)
  - Ellsworth Antarctic Expedition: Reel no. 4, 2nd year, 16mm, Undated (Box S2-2, Folder 16)
  - Ellsworth Antarctic Expedition, Negative, 16mm, ca 1930s (Box S2-2, Folder 17)
  - Ellsworth Antarctic Expedition: 16mm, 1934 (Box S2-2, Folder 18)
  - U.S.-Canadian Weather Station: 16mm, Undated (Box S2-2, Folder 19)
  - Military: testing, 16mm, ca 1940s-1950s (Box S2-2, Folder 20)
  - Military: Clothing Testing, 16mm, ca 1940s-1950s (Box S2-2, Folder 21)
  - Farm (Pennsylvania): 2 reels, 16mm, Undated (Box S2-2, Folder 22)
    VHS video available at 054-310-8, item #45 and 47 (2 copies), 00-07-41-00 thru 00-25-29-00, farm at Montrose
  - Military: Clothing Tests, 16mm, ca 1940s-1950s (Box S2-3, Folder 23)
  - Military: Clothing Tests (Ft. Mead?), Fire Suit, 16mm, ca 1940s-1950s (Box S2-3, Folder 24)
  - Military: Clothing Tests, Fire Suit, 16mm, ca 1940s-1950s (Box S2-3, Folder 25)
  - Ellsworth Antarctic Expedition, 16mm, 1934 (Box S2-3, Folder 26)
  - Military: Clothing and personal equipment - Subarctic R&D (title frame), 16mm, ca 1940s-1950s (Box S2-3, Folder 27)
  - Nautilus: Pieces of film, 35mm, 1931 (Box S2-3, Folder 28)
  - Military: Desert scenes, 16mm, ca 1940s-1950s (Box S2-3, Folder 30)
  - Linguaphone Conversational Russian Course: 15 albums with index, in black hard case, made in England, Undated (Box S-F-1, Folder 1)
  - 16mm Motion Picture Sound Film, "Polar Exploration by Land, Sea, and Air", Film record of exploration of the Arctic and Antarctic Zones, including the 1928-29 expeditions, the 1931 underwater exploration of the arctic by the United States submarine Nautilus, and the Antarctic Expedition (1955-58) conducted under, Undated (Box S-F-1, Folder 2)
    VHS video available at 054-310-8, item 14 and item 21 (2 copies); appears to be a lecture film by Wilkins; for a more complete log of the film, please see the description included with the video, item #14; 41 minutes.; DVD available in 054-310-8
  - Assorted reels of 16mm film, 8x3.5" rollsl 1x7" roll; 2x3.5" reels, boxes in original package, 2 rolls loose film, Undated (Box S-F-1, Folder 3)
  - Assorted Film 16mm (with index), 12x3.5" reels; 1x paper noted index, Undated (Box S-F-1, Folder 4)
- Series VI: Financial Records: Personal, 1930-1969; 3 c.f.
  Personal finances of Sir Hubert Wilkins and Suzanne Wilkins: 1930-1969.
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1941 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1942 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1943 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1944 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1946 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1948 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1949 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1950 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1951 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Checkbooks, 1930-1944 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Checkbooks, 1945-1956 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Receipt and Account Books, 1931-1941 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Receipts and Letters, 1947-1958 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Receipts and Bills, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Cancelled Checks and Letters, 1930-1959 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Bank Notices, 1930-1961 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Itemized Accounts and Letters, 1930-1931 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Itemized Accounts, 1934-1951 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Itemized Accounts and Instructions, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Tax Returns, 1941-1952 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Tax Return and Instructions, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Deposit Tickets (book), 1968-1969 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Notes (book), 1969 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Receipt Book, 1933-1939 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Checkbook, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Checkbook, 1960-1961 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Checkbook, 1961-1962 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Account Book, 1933 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Account Book, 1933-1939 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1933 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1954 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1958 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Bank Records and Statements, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Series VII: Navigational, 1913-1958; 39 c.f.
  This series contains charts, maps, and logbooks. Many are oversized.
  - Fanejord Ship: Papers, 1920-1930 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    renamed Wyatt Earp in 1933
  - The Raft Book, 1943; by Harold Gatty (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - The Raft Book, 1943; by Harold Gatty (Box 27, Folder 3)
    waterproof edition
  - Position, Azimuth and Compass Course Book, undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Dead Reckoning Altitude and Azimuth Table -Bubble Sextant, ca. 1928 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Celestial Air Navigation, 1934 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Navigation with Antarctic Polar Chart, undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - The American Nautical Almanac, 1938 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Air Navigation, 1937; by PVH Weems (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Nautical Books for Sale, undated; by John Bliss and Co., Inc. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Star Altitude Curves: Latitudes 70 Degrees To 90 Degrees and New Line of Position Tables: Weems, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Deck Log Book: revised, August 1918 - April (no date) (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Deck Log Book: revised, August 1918 - May-Sept (no date) (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Bathymetric Map of the Arctic Basin Revised to 1927, carried on submarine Nautilus (Box OV-6, Folder 1)
  - North Pole with Writing - original item number (1), 1946; 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 1)
    Annotated. Color
  - Nansen Sound - original item number (7), 1949 (RV 1954); 22x28 (Box OV-7, Folder 2)
    color
  - Nansen Sound - original item number (7), 1948; 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 3)
  - Robeson Channel: original item number (8), 1948; 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 4)
  - Robeson Channel with Writing - original item number (8), 1950 (RV 1953); 28x22 (Box OV-7, Folder 5)
    Annotated. Color.
  - Independence Fjord - original item number (9), 1947 (RV 1948); 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 6)
    Color
  - Independence Fjord with Writing - original item number (9), 1950 (RV 1951-1952); 22x28 (Box OV-7, Folder 7)
    Color.
  - Humboldt Glacier - original item number (19), 1944; 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 8)
    color.
  - Smith Sound - original item number (20), 1944; 22x28 (Box OV-7, Folder 9)
  - Smith Sound - original item number (20), 1948; 22x28 (Box OV-7, Folder 10)
  - Smith Sound with Writings - original item number (20), 1950 (RV 1951); 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 11)
  - Ellef Ringnes Island - original item number (21), 1944; 22x28 (Box OV-7, Folder 12)
  - Ellef Ringnes Island - original item number (21), 1948; 22x28 (Box OV-7, Folder 13)
  - Prince Patrick Island - original item number (22), 1944; 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 14)
  - Prince Patrick Island - original item number (22), 1948; 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 15)
  - McClure Strait - original item number (35), 1944; 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 16)
  - McClure Strait - original item number (35), 1948; 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 17)
  - Somerset Island - original item number (36), 1945; 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 18)
  - Somerset Island - original item number (36), 1948; 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 19)
  - Bylot Island - original item number (37), 1945; 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 20)
  - Bylot Island - original item number 37, 1948; 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 21)
  - Devil's Thumb - original item number (38), 1944; 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 22)
  - Disko Bay - original item number (57), 1944; 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 23)
  - Arctic Harbour - original item number (58), 1945; 22x28 (Box OV-7, Folder 24)
  - Home Bay - original item number (58), 1945 (RV 1948); 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 25)
  - Gulf of Boothia - original item number (59), 1945; 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 26)
  - Gulf of Boothia - original item number (59), 1945 (RV 1947); 29x22 (Box OV-7, Folder 27)
  - Victoria Strait - original item number (60), 1945; 29x22 (Box OV-7, Folder 28)
  - Victoria Strait - original item number (60), 1945 (RV 1947); 29x22 (Box OV-7, Folder 29)
  - Amundsen Gulf - original item number (61), 1944; 29x22 (Box OV-7, Folder 30)
  - Amundsen Gulf - original item number (61), 1946; 29x22 (Box OV-7, Folder 31)
  - Mackenzie Bay - original item number (62), 1948; 29x22 (Box OV-7, Folder 32)
  - Bathurst Inlet - original item number (80), 1947; 29x22 (Box OV-7, Folder 33)
  - Lake Garry - original item number (81), 1947; 29x22 (Box OV-7, Folder 34)
  - Roes Welcome Sound - original item number (82), 1948; 29x22 (Box OV-7, Folder 35)
  - Foxe Peninsula - original item number (83), 1945 (RV 1948); 29x22 (Box OV-7, Folder 36)
  - Cumberland Peninsula - original item number (84), 1945 (RV 1948); 29x22 (Box OV-7, Folder 37)
  - Cape Cort Adelger with Writing - original item number 109, 1952 (RV 1955); 29x22 (Box OV-7, Folder 38)
  - Wrangell Mountains - original item number (117), 1947; 22x29 (Box OV-7, Folder 39)
  - Tonsing District, Alaska, 1932; 16x22 (Box OV-7, Folder 40)
    B&W
  - Northern Hemisphere, 1945; 65x40 (Box OV-7, Folder 41)
  - Casson Projection of Political Map of the World, New York Journal American, August 9, 1942; 22x17 (Box OV-7, Folder 42)
  - North American January Wind Chill ISO-Cooling Lines, 1942 (Box OV-7, Folder 43)
  - Canada, National Geographic Magazine, 1936; 39x28 (Box OV-7, Folder 44)
  - Alaska, US Dept of Interior Geological Survey, 1947 (RP 1954); 18x25 (Box OV-7, Folder 45)
  - North Polar Stereographic Projection (with symbols apparently signifying locations of air bases, and one map of hand coming from US over the North Pole), ca 1947; 18x19 (Box OV-7, Folder 46)
  - North Polar Stereographic Projection (with symbols apparently signifying locations of air bases, and one map of hand coming from US over the North Pole), ca 1947; 18x19 (Box OV-7, Folder 47)
  - Three cards of maps (numbered 3, 4, and 5) showing approximate locations of US Bomber Bases and US Targets in USSR, 1945-1958 (Box OV-7, Folder 48)
  - Three cards of maps (numbered 3, 4, and 5) showing approximate locations of US Bomber Bases and US Targets in USSR, 1945-1958 (Box OV-7, Folder 49)
  - Three cards of maps (numbered 3, 4, and 5) showing approximate locations of US Bomber Bases and US Targets in USSR, 1945-1958 (Box OV-7, Folder 50)
  - Northern Hemisphere 700 millibar Chart, March 28, 1953; 62x28 (Box OV-7, Folder 51)
    Annotated. B&W
  - Drawn and Pictorial Map of Mt. Hayes, Alaska, 1951 (Box OV-7, Folder 52)
  - Alaska, US Dept of the Interior Geological Survey, 1946 (RP 1947); 48x35 (Box OV-7, Folder 53)
  - Alaska, by Erwin Raisz for Office of Quartermaster General, 1948; 33x39 (Box OV-7, Folder 54)
  - Canada and Greenland Air Charts (with no title, but with added handwriting, 1944 (RV 1951); 45x30 (Box OV-7, Folder 55)
  - Northern Hemisphere Surface Chart, April 30, 1955; 28x37 (Box OV-7, Folder 56)
    Annotated.
  - Northern Hemisphere Surface Chart, April 29, 1955; 28x37 (Box OV-7, Folder 57)
  - Northern Hemisphere Surface Chart, May 1, 1955; 28x37 (Box OV-7, Folder 58)
  - Northern Hemisphere 700 millibar Chart (see #10), March 27, 1953; 30x28 (Box OV-7, Folder 59A)
  - Northern Hemisphere, 700 Millibar Chart, March 27, 1953 (Box OV-7, Folder 59B)
  - Alaska, United States Dept of the Interior Geological Survey, Map E, 1946; 48x36 (Box OV-7, Folder 60)
  - Great Circle Map showing Fairbanks, Alaska, A Geographical Center of Europe, Asia, America, showing Air Distances from Fairbanks to Major Cities, 1930 (RP 1931); 32x25 (Box OV-7, Folder 61)
  - US Air Force Density of Population Chart, GH-7, Northern Hemisphere, 1948; 36x37 (Box OV-7, Folder 62)
  - Proposed Air Lanes over North Pole, Undated (Box OV-7, Folder 63)
  - Routes of Airplane Travel in Alaska by Major Lougee, 1948 (Box OV-7, Folder 64)
  - Essential Combat Footgear, Richardson Highway Zone, Alaska, Undated (Box OV-7, Folder 65)
  - Alaska Railroad Studies, Undated (Box OV-7, Folder 66)
  - Ice Reconnaissance Recording Chart with Correction, 1950 (Box OV-7, Folder 67)
  - North America, The National Geographic Magazine (map is brittle and in pieces), 1924; 35x27 (Box OV-7, Folder 68)
  - Arctic Regions with Pencil Sketchings, Undated (Box OV-7, Folder 69)
  - Richardson Highway and Vicinity, Alaska, Undated (Box OV-7, Folder 70)
  - Delta River District, Alaska, Undated; 18x24 (Box OV-7, Folder 71)
  - The Alaska Railroad, Seward to Matanuska Coal Field, 1940; 48x42 (Box OV-7, Folder 72)
  - Airchart-Seattle, USA to Ketchikan, Alaska, 1946 (RV 1947); 48x15 (Box OV-7, Folder 73)
  - Airchart-Ketchikan, Alaska to Whitehorse, Canada, 1946 (RV 1947); 48x15 (Box OV-7, Folder 74)
  - Alaska Superimposed on Map of US, Undated (Box OV-7, Folder 75)
  - Map of Alaska near Fairbanks, no title, Undated; 18x24 (Box OV-7, Folder 76)
  - Water Currents Map of Canada, Alaska, and Greenland, Undated (Box OV-7, Folder 77)
  - North Polar Projection Map (22 copies) done sketched copy, Undated (Box OV-7, Folder 78)
  - North Polar Projection Map, Pencil Sketch, Undated (Box OV-7, Folder 79)
  - Sketch of Canada (2 copies), Undated (Box OV-7, Folder 80)
  - Sketch of Canada (2 copies), Undated (Box OV-7, Folder 81)
  - Yellowknife Bay, Northwest Territories, Canada, 1944; 31x45 (Box OV-7, Folder 82)
  - Map of Alaska, Kroll Map Company, 1927; 26x33 (Box OV-7, Folder 83)
  - Kroll's Map of Alaska and Western Canada, Undated; 42x33 (Box OV-7, Folder 84)
  - Physical Map of the Arctic, 1929; 18x23 (Box OV-7, Folder 85)
  - North Pacific Ocean and Adjacent Countries, Canada Dept of Mines and Resources, 1935; 13x35 (Box OV-7, Folder 86)
  - The Arctic in our Midst, from the adventure of Wrangel Island by Vilhjamur Stefansson, Published by The MacMillan Co. (4 copies), 1925 (Box OV-7, Folder 87)
  - The Arctic in our Midst, from the adventure of Wrangel Island by Vilhjamur Stefansson, Published by The MacMillan Co. (4 copies), 1925 (Box OV-7, Folder 88)
  - The Arctic in our Midst, from the adventure of Wrangel Island by Vilhjamur Stefansson, Published by The MacMillan Co. (4 copies), 1925 (Box OV-7, Folder 89)
  - The Arctic in our Midst, from the adventure of Wrangel Island by Vilhjamur Stefansson, Published by The MacMillan Co. (4 copies), 1925 (Box OV-7, Folder 90)
  - Pacific Yukon Highway, A Proposed General Route to Alaska, 1930 (Box OV-7, Folder 91)
  - Polar Regions, Rand McNally (10 copies), Undated; 14x19 (Box OV-8, Folder 1)
  - Map of the Antarctic, The American Geographical Society of New York (2 copies), 1928; 42x42 (Box OV-8, Folder 2)
  - Antarctica, US National Committee International Geophysical Year (2 copies), 1957-58; 42x42 (Box OV-8, Folder 3)
  - Document-A New Four-Sheet Planning Map of Antarctica for the Geophysical Year, 1957-58 (Box OV-8, Folder 4)
  - Currents in the Arctic and Antarctic Oceans with printed material, 1920; 26x40 (Box OV-8, Folder 5)
  - Map of the South Pole (?) with Writing on Back, "One of our maps to Mr. Wilkins Fedoron, Shizshow, E Krenpel", Undated; 30x42 (Box OV-8, Folder 6)
    Annotated (minor).
  - Antarctic Water Depth Chart, Dept of the Navy, Hydrographic Office, 1956; 50x35 (Box OV-8, Folder 7)
  - Antarctic Area Stations During International Geophysical Year 1957-58, US Navy Operation "Deep Freeze II", 1956-1957 (Box OV-8, Folder 8)
  - Antarctica, The National Geographic Magazine, with descriptions of important activities/explorations, with handwriting, 1957; 36x29 (Box OV-8, Folder 9)
  - Antarctica, National Mapping Office, Dept of the Interior, 1939 (RV 1956); 30x39 (Box OV-8, Folder 10)
  - Antarctica Relative Accessibility by Ship, 1948 (Box OV-8, Folder 11)
  - Antarctic Regions in 1928 (3 copies) (Box OV-8, Folder 12)
  - South Polar Chart Showing Heights of Land and Depths of Sea (4 copies), ca 1912 (Box OV-8, Folder 13)
  - Map of Antarctica, The American Geographical Society of New York, Sheet I American Quadrant, 1929; 32x32 (Box OV-8, Folder 14)
  - Conquest of Antarctica, Time Magazine Map with Routes of Major Expeditions, Undated (Box OV-8, Folder 15)
  - Queen Mary Land, Australian Antarctic Expedition, 1911-1914 (Box OV-8, Folder 16)
  - Ink Drawing of Various Islands in the Antarctic, Undated; 27x21 (Box OV-8, Folder 17)
  - Separate Ink Drawings of Gough Island, Tristan da Cunha, and Inaccessible and Nightingale I, Undated (Box OV-8, Folder 18)
  - Wilkins Polar Search Map, US Department of Agriculture Weather Map, Weather Bureau, 1937 (Box OV-8, Folder 19)
  - The Graham Land Region Incorporating the Discoveries made by Sir Hubert Wilkins on his Flight of December 20, 1928, 1929 (Box OV-9, Folder 1)
  - Graham Land Showing Sir Hubert Wilkins New Discoveries with Detroit Aviation Society Newsletter, 1929 (Box OV-9, Folder 2)
  - The Field Operations of the Wilkins-Hearst Antarctic Expedition during the season of 1929-30, 1930 (Box OV-9, Folder 3)
  - Antarctic Ocean Sheet VI, Map of Graham Land, with wiring and sketches, 1901; 40x28 (Box OV-9, Folder 4)
  - South Polar Chart with Sketches, 1887 (RV 1914) (Box OV-9, Folder 5)
  - Map of Pacific Ocean with historic flights as of 1928, Including Picture of Wilkins (2 copies), Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 6)
  - Map of Pacific Ocean with Historic Flights as of 1928, including picture of Wilkins (2 copies), Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 7)
  - Map of South Pole (no title) including exploration marks, (3 copies), Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 8)
  - Map of South Pole (no title), Including Exploration Marks (3 copies), Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 9)
  - Map of South Pole (no title), Including Exploration Marks (3 copies), Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 10)
  - Map of Wilkins Submarine Expedition, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 11)
  - Pack Ice Distribution with Sketching, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 12)
  - Wilkins' Arctic Flights with Sketchings, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 13)
  - Geography of the Northlands, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 14)
  - Canada, Showing Main Geological Divisions, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 15)
  - North Alaska, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 16)
  - Bathymetry of the Northern Seas, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 17)
  - Average Annual Maximum Extent of Ice-Cover, Feb-March, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 18)
  - Major Currents of Northern Seas, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 19)
  - Map of Arctic Air Ways, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 20)
  - Map of Arctic Iron Ore Deposits, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 21)
  - Arctic Other Ore Deposits, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 22)
  - Arctic Metal Deposits, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 23)
  - Arctic Limits of Permafrost, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 24)
  - Antarctic, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 25)
  - Arctic Weather Stations, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 26)
  - Soviet Union Average Probability of July and January Cloudiness, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 27)
  - Meteorological Data for One Year for Point Barrow, Alaska, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 28)
  - North Polar Isomagnetic Chart, Epoch 1925, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 29)
  - Arctic Map with Proposed Route of Wilkins' Flight with Sketchings (2 copies), Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 30)
  - Arctic Map with Proposed Route of Wilkins' Flight with Sketchings (2 copies), Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 31)
  - Arctic Institute of North America, Roster of Arctic Specialists, Undated (Box OV-9, Folder 32)
  - Bathymetrical Chart of North Polar Seas by Dr. Fridtjof Nansen, 1926 (Box OV-9, Folder 33)
  - Unknown Regions of the Arctic, 1925 (Box OV-9, Folder 34)
  - North Polar Expedition Sites, Undated; 32x25 (Box OV-9, Folder 35)
  - Alaska Clothing Requirement Areas, 1950; 20x50 (Box OV-9, Folder 36)